Aron Harsfalvi

Full stack Java developer/architect

CONTACT



+36 70 252 8069



aron.harsfalvi@gmail.com



Budapest, Hungary



‡ 1982-09-05



Github: hronnie

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/aronharsfalvi/35/3a0/921

Education and Trainings

BSC, Informatics Engineer @ University of Obuda, John Von Neumann Faculty of Informatics

2001 - 2005

Secure Programming Training @ Walt Disney

2011

Scrum Master Training @ Sprint Consulting

2010

- Basics of Agile paradigms
- Understanding scrum as a simple framework
- Scrum solutions for problems, situations

Oracle @ TCS

2006

- General knowledge of Oracle applications and tools
- Installation of Oracle developer environment
- Usage of Oracle SQL

Initial Learning Program @ TCS

2005-09 - 2005-11

General knowledge of programming techniques, including theory of whole program life cycle.



PROFILE

I'm an Oracle Java certified professional and I have 14 years of development and design experience during which time I have been working with Java and frontend technologies on the full development life-cycle including architecture works. I have knowledge of working on large scale web applications with systems used by millions of people. I have good communication skills which have allowed me to work with clients and international teams. Through my time at my previous workplaces where I worked on projects which allowed me to use a range of technologies including Spring, Hibernate, Relational DBs, HTML and Linux and frontend technologies like Angular, React, etc. I'm an advocate of agile methodologies following Scrum, TDD, CI and Pair programming where possible. I always enjoyed finding the best technologies and creating the design considering the performance, high availability and the security. I am looking for new opportunities in a position where I can utilize my over 14 years of experience at Java development and design. I am a dynamic, result -oriented person, who likes to work individually and as part of a team. I like change and I am fast learner, ready for anything new.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer (Contract) -

@ Smatrics GmbH, Budapest, Wien

2019-01 - today

After I had a short onboarding process learning the basic concepts and protocols (Charging Point Operator) of the electric vehicle charging process (learn more at https://www.hubject.com), I was helping to build a charging management system which helped managing and maintaining the charging related processes and data (Charging Unit, Users, Charging sessions, alarm, remote control, etc management).

I mainly worked on the Frontend using React visualizing the charging protocol in a responsive and user-friendly way. My other tasks were to implement missing protocol items and other new features on the backend.

Technical:

Java, Spring Boot, MySQL, React

Senior Java Developer Senior Java and Angular Developer (Contract) -@ MSCI Hungary Kft, Budapest

2018-10 - 2018-12

I'm developing well separated features/applications that serves creating Indexes and other benchmark tools for the stock market. My goal here is to drastically reduce time-to-market of new index products by providing a resilient, scalable and user-friendly platform, used by both research and IT personnel.

- Java and J2EE program languages.
- Soft skills: team spirit, presentational skills

SKILLS

JAVA

SPRING

ANGULAR

NODE JS

DESIGN

WEB

JAVASCRIPT

CSS

CERTIFICATES

OCAJP7 Certification (1Z0-803 Java SE 7 Programmer I)

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (fluent)
HUNGARIAN (native)

INTERESTS

I enjoy sports, reading, nature and spiritual activities)

To achieve this goal, I'm using the latest cutting-edge technologies such as Angular, Spring Boot and Websockets.

Technical:

Java, Spring Boot, Angular 5

Senior Java Developer (Contract) -

@Aliz (aka Doctusoft), Budapest

2018-01 - 2018-08

I was working on a banking project for SIX Group. This application helps parties to organize larger scale investments and the clients can agree in various terms and conditions. This is a Java 8 web application using ZK framework. Along with other team members I created the frontend part of the application covering every functionality.

Technical:

Java, Spring Boot, ZK, Tomcat, CSS, Javascript

Web Solution Architect -

@Avon Cosmetics Hungary Kft, Budapest

2016-05 - 2017-10

I was working with business partners primarily in Central and Eastern Europe to assess feasibility of requirements and map those requirements to high-performance web solutions and also overseeing and participating in the design and development of new features, improvements and bug fixes.

Responsibility:

- Creating design for e-commerce applications which are running on Java/Spring, WebSphere Application Server, Oracle and associated components. These solutions included a modern browser-side experience with mobile-friendly responsive design use of REST API.
- Reusing existing design to other markets.
- Conducting code reviews and ensure that high standards are met for code quality, performance and security.
- Working with infrastructure partners to ensure that necessary hardware and software is provisioned and configured to support the solution.
- Working across the organization to help improve the development, testing, release and documentation standards.

Senior Java Developer - @Chemaxon, Budapest

2015-11 - 2016-04

I'm Chemaxon is a software company who provides chemistry solutions for pharmacy companies. I was gathering requirements, designing and implementing new features. One of my main task was developing Single Sign On (SSO) solution for the existing products:

- Discovering the current authentication and authorization process
- Analysing the possible technologies and solutions
- Creating the design for SSO
- Helping in the implementation of SSO
- Configuration of an SSO provider using PKI based authentication

Technical:

Java, Spring, Spring Security, AngularJS, MySQL, Git, Maven, Tomcat, Eclipse, Linux

Senior Java Developer - @Kainos Software Ltd, London

2014-08 - 2015-09

Project #01

In my first project at Kainos my main task was to build an agricultural application for the British government (Department for Environment Food & Department (Department for Environment Food & Department (Department for Environment Food & Department Food & Department for Environment Food & Department Food & Department

- Development scope and Responsibility:
- Analysis and planning, refinement of user stories
- Providing map based frontend solutions using AngularJS 1.x
- Implementing backend API
- Working closely with customer and Business analysts to refine requirements

Project #02

I was also taking part in another governmental project (FCO – Foreign & Commonwealth Office) where we built an online form application for requesting ETD (Emergency Travel Document) integrating that with several external services such as case management system, printing service, email sending service, etc.

Development scope and Responsibility:

- Knowledge transfer from the Foreign Office
- Forming the agile team and methodologies
- Choosing best technologies and helping to create the project framework structure
- Analysis and planning, refinement of user stories
- Implementing the project using Scala, NodeJS, React and other backend/frontend technologies

Key achievements

Designing and building an application from the very beginning to the end

Technical:

AngularJS, REACT, NodeJS, RequireJS, Karma, Java, Spring, Scala, Hibernate, REST, dropWizard, HTTP/HTTPS protocol, Oracle DB, TeamCity, Jenkins, GIT, SBT, Nginx, Eclipse/Idea, Mac OS X

Senior Java Developer (Contract) -

@Cube19, London

2014-06 - 2014-07

cube19 is a startup company that helps recruitment companies to significantly improve sales performance and create competition with recruitment analytics. I was part of the backend development team who created new features for the existing system. E.g.: adding new reporting functionalities.

Technical:

Java, J2EE, JMS Hibernate, REST, RestEasy, HTTP/HTTPS protocol, MySQL/Stored procedures, Jenkins, GIT, Maven, JBoss, Eclipse, Windows

Senior Java Developer (Contract) - @Weapon7, London

2014-02 - 2014-04

I continued my previous work (see below description for Weapon7)

Senior Java Developer (Contract) - @Medicanimal, London

2013-11 - 2014-02

I continued my previous work on-site (see below description for Medicanimal)

Senior Java Developer (Contract) @Weapon7, London

2013-05 - 2013-09

Building REST web service API for an online meditation portal (headspace.com) which has more than 50 thousand daily users. My main responsibility was to develop new web services. Besides building the internal functionalities. I also managed to integrate some third-party e-commerce tools and payment gateways such as PayPal and Zuora.

Key achievements

Introducing 3rd party payment, mailing and subscription engine on the backend

Technical:

Java, Spring, Hibernate, REST, CXF, HTTP/HTTPS protocol, MySQL, Jenkins, SVN, Maven, Glassfish, Eclipse, Linux

Java Developer @Scientific Games Kft, Budapest

2012-05 - 2013-04

Development scope and Responsibility:

Designing new features for gambling applications

Taking part in web and terminal based project implementations (full-stack)

Technical:

Java, Spring, Apache tomcat, Oracle SQL, Eclipse (used for Java), Linux, Windows, Maven, Junit, HTML, HTTP protocol, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bash, CVS, Remedy

Java Developer @Medicanimal, Budapest

2011-09 - 2012-02

Development scope and Responsibility:

- Developing administrator interface where admins can build, customize and set up registration functionalities both at backend and frontend site
- Implementing and designing new features for medicanimal.com using an ERP system
- Investigating and providing solutions for system defects
- Providing SQL queries for business requirements (for reporting purpose)

Technical:

Java, PostgreSQL, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, Linux (Ubuntu), Bash, Junit, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, HTTP protocol, Track, Ant

Java Developer @Walt Disney Hungary Kft, Budapest

2010-01 - 2011-08

As a member of Disney Interactive Media Group, I developed and supported the Disney international registration and login system.

I was participating in developing new functionalities and supporting the working version of the application for internal administrators and external developers (both client and server side). I was developing a large-scale web application which has several components including the registration system, favourites, like function and other smaller functionalities which were integrated for other Disney online applications like online games.

This application was used by around 2 million people daily.

Key achievements

I integrated our registered user outside of US into US database via building an API

Technical

Java, Spring, Sprint MVC, JSP, JDBC, Web Services (REST and SOAP), Axis2, CXF, JaxB, MsSQL, Apache Tomcat, Ajax, Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, HTTP/HTTPS protocol, Eclipse, Bash, XML, XSD, Linux (Ubuntu), CVS, SVN, TeamCity, Jira, Ant, Maven

Java Developer @AdNovum Hungary Kft, Budapest

2007-09 - 2009-11

I was developing and maintaining internal UBS Bank web applications developing smaller features and taking care of defects. It also included a 2 months training in Zurich where I learned the know-how of the project, future plans and working out the best solutions for the design and technologies. I was also responsible to transfer the gathered information to the Hungarian team and provide the necessary support.

I was involved in several internal projects such as time tracking tool, booking system, proxy configuration.

Technical:

Java, JSP, Struts, Spring, Hibernate, JBoss, Weblogic, Apache, Oracle, MySql, PHP, XML, XSD, Javascript, HTML, CSS, HTTP/HTTPS protocol, Eclipse, Bash, Linux (OpenSuSe), Solaris, CVS, SVN, Ant

Junior Java Developer @Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), Budapest

2005-10 - 2007-08

I After finishing my 6 weeks training in India I continued my training in Java through a GE web project which managed the renting process for buildings. I created screens for the web application and smaller helper tools.

I was also involved in smaller projects for GE Money creating new features, fixing defects and in other integration tasks.

Responsibility:

- Developing and maintaining of Java web applications (full-stack)
- Searching and integrating new technologies

Technical:

Java, JSP, Struts, Hibernate, Oracle, Javascript, HTML, CSS, HTTP/HTTPS protocol, Weblogic, JBoss, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, Windows, Ant